<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>

<class package="nape.phys" name="Material">
	<file>Material.hx</file>
	<description>
		<text>Physics Material giving shapes density,elasticity and frictional values.</text>	
	</description>
	<short>
		Physics Material
	</short>
	
	<property name="elasticity" type="Float">
		<description> How elastic the material is</description>
		<detail>
			<description><text>The higher the elasticity, the more elastic the material is.</text><br/><text>0 elasticity corresponds to total inelasticity, 1 corresponds to complete elasticity.</text><br/><br/>
			<text class="small1">Note that values higher than 1 are perfectly acceptable but will not make the material any more elastic, however doing this can be useful to influence the resultant pair-wise elasticity coefficient calculated when shape/particles interact which is a combination of the two elastic coefficients. For example setting elasticity to Math.POSITIVE_INFINITY will mean that whenever this shape collides with something, it will ALWAYS be completely elastic (unless the other material has -inf as elasticity)</text><br/>
			<br/><text class="small1">Equally, values lower than 0 are also acceptable, and will serve to decrease the combined elasticity of interacting shapes, with Math.NEGATIVE_INFINITY acting to never allow elastic behaviour.</text> </description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="staticFriction" type="Float">
		<description> Coefficient of static friction for the material</description>
		<detail>
			<description><text>The higher the coef. of static friction, the harder it is to cause the shape to slide from a standstill</text><br/><text>0 corresponds to no static friction, and any finite positive value is allowed.</text></description>
			
			<set><code inline="true">staticFriction &lt; 0</code> </set>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="dynamicFriction" type="Float">
		<description> Coefficient of dynamic/kinetic friction for the material</description>
		<detail>
			<description><text>The higher the coef. of dynamic friction, the quicker a sliding shape will come to a standstill</text><br/><text>0 corresponds to no dynamic friction, and any finite positive value is allowed.</text></description>
			
			<set><code inline="true">dynamicFriction &lt; 0</code> </set>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="rollingFriction" type="Float">
		<description> Coefficient of rolling friction for the material</description>
		<detail>
			<description><text>The higher this coef. the quicker a rolling circle will come to rest, although rolling friction only occurs when one shape is a circle, it is still of use to set this coefficient on polygons for example, the predefined sand material has a very high rolling friction so that when used on say the ground, a rolling circle will quickly come to rest even though the ground itself is not a circle.</text></description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="density" type="Float">
		<description> Density of material </description>
		<detail>
			<description><text>The density of a material (measured in g/px^2) corresponds to how much mass a shape will have per unit area.</text><br/><text>Density must be strictly positive</text></description>
			
			<set><code inline="true">density &lt;= 0</code> </set>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property/>
	
	<property name="shapes" type="ShapeList" readonly="true">
		<description> Immutable list of active shapes using material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Reference to an immutable list of active shapes that make use of this material. Active shapes refers to those currently inside of a Space object. </description>
		</detail>
	</property>

	<constructor>
		<arg name="elasticity" optional="true" type="Float" default="0"/>
		<arg name="dynamicFriction" optional="true" type="Float" default="1"/>
		<arg name="staticFriction" optional="true" type="Float" default="2"/>
		<arg name="density" optional="true" type="Float" default="1"/>
		<arg name="rollingFriction" optional="true" type="Float" default="0.01"/>
		<description> Construct new Material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Construct new Material </description>
		</detail>
	</constructor>
	
	<method name="copy" return="Material" const="true">
		<description> Produce a copy of the material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Produce a copy of this material. </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	
	<method name="wood" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Wooden material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of wood </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="steel" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Steel material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of steel </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="ice" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Ice material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of ice </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="rubber" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Rubber material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of rubber </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="glass" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Glass material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of glass </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="sand" static="true" inline="true" return="Material">
		<description> Sand material </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Returns a new Material intended to model properties of sand </description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	
</class>
</data>
