<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>

<class package="nape.dynamics" name="InteractionFilter">
	<file>InteractionFilter.hx</file>
	<short>Filtering values for collisions/fluids/sensing</short>
	<description><text>Provides bit masking values to use in efficient filtering of collisions/fluids/sensing</text><br/><br/>
	<text>Two shapes will interact iff. </text><code inline="true">(a.group&amp;b.mask != 0) &amp;&amp; (b.group&amp;a.mask != 0)</code><br/><text>Default values are such that all shapes would be only in a single group (1) and would interact with everything</text><br/><br/><text>Note that there are only 32 real groups (0-31) as each group corresponds to a set bit in the integer. so the group '0x120' corresponds to the real groups 5 and 8 since 0x120 = (1&lt;&lt;5)|(1&lt;&lt;8) </text> <br/><br/><text>Fluid interactions have highest precedence, followed by collisions and then interaction as sensors.</text><br/><br/><text>Fluid interactions will not occur under any circumstances between two kinematic/static shapes, in which case collisions will have the highest precedence and fluid interactions will be ignored.</text><br/><br/><text>Collisions will never occur between two non-static shapes, in which case sensing (being the only thing left at this point) will have the highest precedence.</text><br/><br/><text>Sensing will never occur between two static shapes.</text></description>
	
	<property name="collisionGroup" type="Int">
		<description>collision groups</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will reside in for purposes of collisions</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	<property name="collisionMask" type="Int">
		<description>collision mask; which groups to collide with</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will be allowed to collide with</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="sensorGroup" type="Int">
		<description>sensor groups</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will reside in for purposes of sensing</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	<property name="sensorMask" type="Int">
		<description>sensor mask; which groups to sense with</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will be allowed to sense with</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property name="fluidGroup" type="Int">
		<description>fluid interaction groups</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will reside in for purposes of fluid interactions</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	<property name="fluidMask" type="Int">
		<description>fluid interaction mask; which groups to flow with</description>
		<detail>
			<description>set bits correspond to which groups shapes will be allowed to interact via fluid interactions with</description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<property/>
	<property name="shapes" type="ShapeList" readonly="true">
		<description> Immutable list of active shapes using filter </description>
		<detail>
			<description> Reference to an immutable list of active shapes that make use of this filter. Active shapes referring to those currently inside of a Space. </description>
		</detail>
	</property>
	
	<constructor>
		<arg name="collisionGroup" type="Int" optional="true" default="1"/>
		<arg name="collisionMask" type="Int" optional="true" default="0xffffffff"/>
		<arg name="sensorGroup" type="Int" optional="true" default="1"/>
		<arg name="sensorMask" type="Int" optional="true" default="0xffffffff"/>
		<arg name="fluidGroup" type="Int" optional="true" default="1"/>
		<arg name="fluidMask" type="Int" optional="true" default="0xffffffff"/>
		
		<description>Construct new InteractionFilter</description>
		<detail>
			<description>Construct new InteractionFilter</description>
		</detail>
	</constructor>
	
	<method name="copy" return="InteractionFilter" const="true">
		<description>Produce a copy of this interaction filter</description>
		<detail>
			<description>Produce a copy of this interaction filter.</description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	
	<method/>
	<method name="shouldCollide" return="Bool" const="true">
		<arg name="filter" type="InteractionFilter" const="true"/>
		<description>Test if filters will allow collision</description>
		<detail>
			<description>If true, two shapes with these filters will be allowed to collide (Lest there are other considerations that prevent them doing so)</description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="shouldSense" return="Bool" const="true">
		<arg name="filter" type="InteractionFilter" const="true"/>
		<description>Test if filters will allow sensing</description>
		<detail>
			<description>If true, two shapes with these filters will be allowed to sense (Lest there are other considerations that prevent them doing so)</description>
		</detail>
	</method>
	<method name="shouldFlow" return="Bool" const="true">
		<arg name="filter" type="InteractionFilter" const="true"/>
		<description>Test if filters will allow fluid interaction</description>
		<detail>
			<description>If true, two shapes with these filters will be allowed to interact via fluid interactions (Lest there are other considerations that prevent them doing so such as not having fluid interaction enabled on a shape)</description>
			<seealso><link type="class" href="Shape" anchor="fluidEnabled">Shape::fluidEnabled</link> </seealso>
		</detail>
	</method>
	
</class>
</data>
